# **Kuan-Hung Yeh**

https://peterntuph.github.io/

# **PROFILE**

I am currently a graduate of the Department of Public Health, National Taiwan University. My research interest lies at the intersection of Causal Inference and Statistical Genetics, recently on the development and application of novel Mendelian Randomization to control the pleiotropic effects. B05801047@ntu.edu.tw
☐ (+886)-956073355

7F., No. 536, Linsen N. Rd., Zhongshan Dist., Taipei City Taiwan (R.O.C.)

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

**Taiwan Public Health Association** | Jul.2020 – Present Research Assistant | *Advisor: <u>Tzu-Pin Lu</u> & <u>Hsien-Ho Lin</u>* 

 Designed automatic mask detection system in project of "Postpandemic lifestyle behavior monitoring" commissioned by Taiwan Centers for Disease Control (CDC).

**Biostatistics & Bioinformatics lab, NTU** | Jun.2019 – Feb.2020 Undergraduate Researcher | *Advisor: Tzu-Pin Lu* 

- Constructed a robust prognostic model typically for Asian colon cancer patients with Harrell c-index near 0.75.
- **Poster Presentation** in 2019 Taiwan Public Health Joint Annual Conference. [Poster Link]
- Won **Best Topic Research Poster Award** in CPH, NTU.
- Granted by **College Student Research Scholarship**, Ministry of Science and Technology, Taiwan.
- Under review by **the Cancer Letters**.

**Dept of Medical Research, TVGH** | Jun.2019 – Aug.2019 Research Intern | *Advisor: Tzu-Hung Hsiao* 

- Carried out a GWAS on Metabolic Syndrome in Subjects with Abdominal Obesity in a Taiwanese Population. [Poster Link]
- Accepted Poster by 2020 IEEE International Conference on Bioinformatics and Biomedicine (IEEE BIBM 2020)

**Inst of Information Science, Academia Sinica** | Summer.2018 Summer Research Intern | *Advisor: Da-Wei Wang* 

Built Diagnosis Related Groups (DRGs) on Ophthalmology using
 Machine & Deep Learning algorithms. [Github Link]

## **EDUCATION**

# **National Taiwan University**

Bachelor of Science, Public Health

**Program: Biostatistics** 

Infectious Diseases

Cumulative GPA: 3.75/4.0 (WES)

# **LANGUAGE**

# **Advanced Proficiency in English**

GRE (2019, 12)

Verbal: 152 (54th Percentile)

Quantitative: 167 (89th Percentile)

Analytical Writing: 3.0

TOEFL (2020, 09)

Reading: 29 Speaking: 22 Listening: 28 Writing: 21

Total: 100

# Native Proficiency in Mandarin Basic Proficiency in Japanese

## **SKILLS**

#### **Statistical Tools:**

R Language (Proficient) SAS (Basic), SQL (Basic)

# **Programming:**

Python (Proficient)

Markdown (Basic)

# **HONOR & AWARDS**

2020	•	Honor Graduate in College of Public Health, NTU
2020	T	<b>nonor Graduate</b> in College of Public Health, N

Nominee of Elite Scholarship from Elite-Well Education Foundation

#### 2019

Nominee of Dr. KP CHEN Memorial Scholarship

- ♦ Dr. KP CHEN is the father of public health in Taiwan, whose most well-known contribution is to clarify the causality between Blackfoot disease and Arsenicosis.
- ♦ Dr. KP CHEN Memorial Scholarship is one of the highest award for public health undergraduates in TAIWAN.

#### 2018

Nominee of **Dr. Jiang Jian Memorial Scholarship** from NTUPH

2017

- Certificate of Taiwan Medical Information Manager
- Certificate of Complete CITI program in Biomedical Human Subject Research

# **COMPETITIONS**

## 2018 TMU x MIT (Sana) HIOT Hackathon | Oct.2018

1st Prize with NT\$80,000 (out of 20 teams) [News Link]

- A hackathon organized by Taipei Medical University and MIT Sana Global Team, Boston.
- Proposed an Ultrasound Assisting System for examination of internal hemorrhage with 93% accuracy rate.

# **2018 Hack x Heart** | Sep.2018

# Top 12 teams (out of 60 teams)

- A hackathon organized by Taiwan Heart Foundation and Ministry of Science and Technology.
- Built an app to increase medication adherence among patient with acute coronary syndrome.
- Won Innovation Award from Xin Chen Medical Research Foundation and School of Pharmacy, NTU.

# **ACTIVITIES**

# **29th Health Services & Dedication Award** | *Volunteer Investigator* **Highest official award for medical personnel in TAIWAN (R.O.C.)**

Aug.2019

- Represented the Legislative Yuan to interview the award nominee.
- Made a presentation in Legislative Yuan for committee to vote for award winner

#### **Public Health Student Association** | *Vice president*

Aug.2018 – Aug.2019

- Engaged in curriculum general meeting and uphold student's right to education
- Organized and negotiated with the school authorities for providing more students space

#### **Public Health Summer Service Team** | Leader of Logistics Section

Oct.2018 - Jul.2019

- Raised total \$10,000 USD from Nonprofit Organizations and Foundations.
- Guided 90 students to advocate health promotion in Tainan for a week.